FATEMEH (SABA) MARZOUGHI (she/her)

Software Developer

Personal Info:

- github.com/fatemehmarzoughi
- in/sabamarzoughi
- Iran-Tehran
- (98)919-5062977
- saba.marzoughi18@gmail.com

About Me:

A software developer with three years of full-time experience in frontend development, accompanied by two years of part-time learning and practice in this domain. Throughout this professional journey, valuable experience has been acquired in the development of diverse projects, enhancing proficiency in the JavaScript programming language and associated development tools. In leisure moments, focus is directed towards self-improvement and the creation of personal projects. Eagerly anticipating the next challenge to engage in the development and implementation of mobile/web applications while contributing to a robust software engineering team.

Skills:

- Programming Languages
 - JavaScript, TypeScript
- Front-end technologies
 - HTML5, CSS3, SASS
 - React
- Design
 - OOP, FP
- Cross Platform Apps:
 - React-Native (Android, iOS)
 - Electron (Windows, MacOS)
- State Managements
 - Redux. Context
- ALM
 - GitOps
 - Postman
 - Jira, Trello, Figma
- CMS
 - Starpi
 - WordPress
- DB solutions
 - Realm
- API paradigms
 - REST, GraphQL

Education:

Sep 2017 - Dec 2021

 Bachelor of Computer Engineering (Software)

Professional Experiences:

Front-end developer at UniPlato:

Australia (Remote),

The recommendation letter

Aug 2022 – May 2023

Uniplato is a team consisting of more than 15 members developing the "Coffee" platform, a meeting platform for scheduling and managing meetings with individuals or groups of

Visit Proiect

- Upgraded the "Coffee" platform by refactoring the old code structures of 2 old modules and bringing the modules back to the project.
- Enhanced platform stability by conducting more than 5 code reviews for new team members.
- Strengthened the codebase by developing over 15 pixel-perfect, responsive and well-structured **React** components, making the components accessible to all team members across all the modules as part of the project design system.
- Delivered over 10 new features, complete with demos, to the platform through collaborative communication with team members and the adept utilization of REST API and web sockets.
- Directed the Mac desktop app functionalities, prioritising features and managing development to align with user needs and business objectives.
- Collaborated with the new/junior team members to tackle challenges and overcome obstacles besides working independence in each task.

Front-end developer at Comfortel:

The recommendation letter

Russia (Remote),

Visit Project

Dec 2021 – May 2022

Comfortel is an Internet service provider company the team consists of over 15 members developing the "**Techpal**" project which consists of different platforms: Inkpal, Chatpal, and Gitpal.

- Elevated team communication by implementing customization across the Mattermost platform, ensuring a seamless experience on desktop (Windows and Mac) using **Electron** and mobile on Android operating system.
- Enhanced the usability of the "**Techpal**" platform by launching the desktop application on three different operating systems (Windows, mac, and Linux) with Electron, while also developing the Android application using **React-Native**.
- Documented the codes, ensuring that provides clear explanations for other developers to easily comprehend different sections of the codebase.

Front-end developer (Freelancing and Open-source):

Tehran, <u>Visit Project</u> Nov 2020 – Dec 2021

MyPlayer is an open-source React Native project, serving as an audio/video provider platform. This platform utilizes Strapi as the CMS and available on both iOS and Android OS.

- Transitioned from class-base structures to functional ones, to harness the power of hooks. This transformation let to a remarkable performance enhancement particularly noticeable on older Android devices.
- Refactored old code structure that resulted in removing 3 useless and extra packages from the project and reduced the bundle size.

Front-end developer at Bytino:

Tehran, Visit Project Nov 2019 – Nov 2020

Bytino is a startup team comprising frontend, backend, and designer members with the primary mission being the creation of outstanding web pages.

- Improved team's portfolio resulting in the acquisition of 2 new projects by creating one-page websites that showcased the team capability.
- Created 2 web pages templates that have the potential to expedite project implementation.
- Resized businesses customers by 10% with creating webpages using WordPress.